Highly organized and responsible PHP software engineer with strong problem-solving skills. Fast learner with the ability to quickly adapt to new technologies. Excellent communication skills and a track record of successful project completion. Experienced in developing and maintaining web applications using PHP, Node.js, Typescript and various frameworks. Proven ability to work effectively in a team environment and lead the development process.

Work History

2022-01 -Current

Solution Architect, Tech Lead

LTD Web3App.agency, Riga

- Worked with customers or prospective customers to develop integrated solutions and lead detailed architectural dialogues to facilitate delivery of comprehensive solution.
- Drafted assemblies, models and other technical drawings.
- Validated adherence to best practices, quality standards and customer specifications.
- Prioritized tasks and planned workflows to meet operational targets.
- Managed project planning, resource allocation, scope, schedule, status and documentation.
- Conducted technical workshops for customers and development team.
- Delivered all projects to customers and made sure they are satisfied with outcome.

2021-01 -Current

Freelance Software Engineer

Toptal, Riga

 Provided numerous technical, blockchain, crypto and Web3 consultations

2017-04 -2022-11

PHP Backend Developer

Paybis LTD, Riga

- Added support of more than 60 cryptocurrencies to project, company's turnover grew drastically afterwards.
- Helped refactoring legacy business logic by splitting mono-repository to micro-services.
- Designed and implemented more than 10 different micro-services to project.
- Reviewed hundreds of Merge Requests

Igor Abramov

Software Engineer

Contact

Address

Riga, Latvia, LV-1057

Phone

(+371) 26971909

E-mail

abramov.igor.n@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/igor-abramov-815484143

Skills

PHP

Excellent

Git, Gitlab

Excellent

Symfony

Excellent

SQL

Excellent

Object Oriented
Programming

Excellent

Amazon Web Services

Very Good

Docker

Very Good

Terraform

Good

preventing critical bugs, incorrectly implemented features and badly structured code.

- Managed releases using Gitlab, CI/CD
- Wrote dozens of Technical Designs and supported project's technical documentation constantly updating it.
- Performed troubleshooting of technical issues within production environment, deployed hot-fixes.
- Mentored junior developers on company's coding conventions and rules, industry best practices and techniques.
- Configured and deployed existing and future REST APIs, integrating with third-party APIs.
- Collaborated with project managers and developers to define parameters and plan detailed specifications with clear project deliverables and timelines.
- Wrote hundreds of PHP Unit tests, integration tests, feature tests and pact contract tests.

Education

2000-09 -2011-06

High School Diploma

Pushkin Lyceum - Riga, Latvia

No Degree: European Business Studies

RISEBA - Riga

Interests

Reading

Fitness

Snowboard

Motorcross

